Finding Aid for the Carey McWilliams Papers LSC.1319
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 2. Correspondence and research files, 1896-1982; 38 boxes
  - 2B. Files on subjects, 1914-1982; 20 boxes
    - Ethnics (3 of 3), 1967-1979; ca. 50 items. (Box 72, Folder 7)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include civil rights, desegregation, racism, and universities and minorities.
    - Evangelicals (1 of 3), 1965, 1972-1980; 17 items. (Box 72, Folder 8)
      Press release, a copy of the Voice, and clippings.
    - Evangelicals (2 of 3), 1977-1979; ca. 70 items. (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Evangelicals (3 of 3), 1977-1979; ca. 70 items. (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1944, 1952-1964, 1975-1980; 44 items. (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with R.B. Hood and Paul Harrison. Memoranda and photocopies about the FBI files on the ACLU, including an ACLU testimony report on charter legislation entitled, "Controlling the FBI." Justice Department Watch newsletters, and assorted clippings.
    - Foreign Guest Workers, 1976-1979; 12 items. (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Press release and newspaper clippings. Also includes Worldwatch Paper 33 "International Migration: The Search for Work" by Kathleen Newman.
    - Hispanics (1 of 2), 1966-1970, 1975-1979; 17 items. (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Correspondence with Dr. Jaime Sena-Rivera and Jennifer Hurtsfeld, a letter from Priscilla Falcon, a report by Hurtsfeld entitled, "Identity, Assimilation and the Social Question: The Mexican Americans in Los Angeles," press releases, clippings, a newsletter, and a Mexican-American Study Project progress report.
    - Hispanics (2 of 2), 1961, 1969-1979; ca. 70 items. (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include oil, politics, health, the arts, churches, schools, San Francisco and Los Angeles populations, and United States/Mexico relations.
    - Hollywood, 1927-1934, 1974-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Handwritten note, a copy of Panorama (with an article, "The Hollywood Gesture," by McWilliams) an image by Wm. Shaw, and clippings.
    - Hollywood Hussars, 1935; 9 items. (Box 73, Folder 6)
      1 telegraph from Jack Moss, handwritten notes, the Hollywood Hussars' brochure, and newspaper clippings.
    - Illegal Aliens and Immigration, 1979-1980; ca. 50 items. (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Illegals--1979, 1978-1979; ca. 50 items. (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include United States/Mexico border, the census, and Mexican immigrants.
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service Raids--Racial Violence, 1979-1980; ca. 20 items. (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Innovations, 1967-1968, 1976-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 73, Folder 10)
      Letter from Dr. Ira M. Robinson, press releases, clippings (mostly newspaper), and a pamphlet entitled, "Present Value, Constructing a Sustainable Future" from the State of California's Office of Planning and Research. Subjects include societal trends and the environment.
  - 2C. General correspondence, 1923-1980; 6 boxes
    This subseries contains McWilliams's main body of personal and professional correspondence that was not originally filed by him in folders under the names of individual people or topics. Additional correspondence may be found throughout the collection, particularly in the files on people (see Subseries 2A), his publisher correspondence (see Subseries 2D), his lecture files (see Series 5), his The Nation files (see Series 7, box 86), and within his papers relating to the publication of major monographs (see Subseries 6E). McWilliams kept his original correspondence files in an approximate chronological fashion. To preserve the integrity of the original order of these materials, this subseries was arranged chronologically. The names of important or interesting correspondents are given at the folder level.
    - Correspondence, undated; 12 items. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Letters from F. Scott Fitzgerald (photocopies), Gwen Cash, V.F. Calverton, E.A. von Westphalen, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1923-1924; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Photocopies of letters concerning McWilliams's suspension from the University of Southern California and subsequent reinstatement.
    - Correspondence, 1925-1927; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Letters from Eda W. Blackmer (photocopy), Mrs. VanWyck Brooks, Floyd Dell, Lillian Friend Marcus, and S. Swall.
    - Correspondence, 1928-1929; 7 items. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Letters from Gertrude Atherton (photocopies), and Wilbur Macey Stone. Also includes clippings.
    - Correspondence, 1930; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Letters from Harold D. Carew, T. H. Bell, and Harry A. Potamkin.
    - Correspondence, 1931; 9 items. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Letters from P. D. Perkins, Charmian London, the University of Southern California, Lella Clough, and Althea Warren. Also contains a four-page letter by McWilliams that he calls a "footnote" to John T. Flynn's article, "Graft in Business."
    - Correspondence, 1932-1934; 9 items. (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Letters from John Jay Chapman, Harry Carlisle, Henry E. "Pat" Stubbs, Henry Smith, and Hamilton Stark. Also includes a clipping.
    - Correspondence, 1935; 10 items. (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Letters. Also contains a manuscript by T. H. Bell.
    - Correspondence, 1936; 17 items. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Letters from William Soskin, Edwin Buckalew, James Farrell, and others. Also contains letters related to the Progressive State Committee Supporting Roosevelt for President.
    - Correspondence, 1937; 13 items. (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Letters from David Anderson, G.R. MacMinn, and others. Also contains letters related to the American League Against War and Fascism.
    - Correspondence, 1938; 24 items. (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Letters from Julia Coolidge Altrocchi, Jackson Barber, Charles Wakefield Cadman, Elizabeth Forman, and the Lawyers Committee on American Relations with Spain. Also contains the Preliminary Report of The Committee on Labor Education, and correspondence with Herbert Resner discussing the possibility of McWilliams's being appointed Chief of the Division of Immigration and Housing.
    - Correspondence, 1939; 19 items. (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Letters from Leonard Austin, Milton Abernethy, and others. Many congratulate McWilliams on his being appointed Chief of the Division of Immigration and Housing Commission. Also contains a 12-page open letter To All Active Supporters of Democracy and Peace, a statement of recommendation for Loren Miller, and a letter protesting Charles Kramer's appointment to the United States District Court in Los Angeles.
    - Correspondence, 1940-1941; 16 items. (Box 25, Folder 13)
      Letters, mostly from people referring to hearing McWilliams speak on the radio program America's Town Meeting of the Air. Also contains one from the U.S. Department of Labor congratulating McWilliams for receiving a Guggenheim Fellowship.
    - Correspondence, 1941-1943; 62 items. (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Mostly letters from people referring to hearing McWilliams speak on the radio program America's Town Meeting of the Air. Also includes a letter from Jessica McManus Paul.
    - Correspondence, 1942-1943; 15 items. (Box 25, Folder 15)
      Primarily letters from people referring to Brothers Under the Skin or to hearing McWilliams speak on the radio program America's Town Meeting of the Air.
    - Correspondence, 1944; 18 items. (Box 25, Folder 16)
      Letters from James Pope, and others, including some related to McWilliams's lecture appearances.
    - Correspondence, 1945; 12 items. (Box 25, Folder 17)
      Letters, including some pertaining to Prejudice.
    - Correspondence, 1946; 20 items. (Box 25, Folder 18)
      Letters from Phil Townsend Hanna, Will Rogers, Jr., Helen Louise Johnston, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1947; 17 items. (Box 25, Folder 19)
      Letters from Robert K. Carr, George H. Dunne, Saul Alinsky, and others. Includes a manuscript by Joseph Kinsey Howard, and a signed agreement.
    - Correspondence, 1948; 21 items. (Box 25, Folder 20)
      Includes letters related to McWilliams's lecture appearances and congratulations on A Mask for Privilege.
    - Correspondence, 1948-1951; 31 items. (Box 25, Folder 21)
      Correspondence relating to McWilliams's being accused of communist leanings. Includes letters from Robert Kenny.
    - Correspondence, 1949; 22 items. (Box 25, Folder 22)
      Contains letters related to McWilliams's honors, lecture appearances, and North from Mexico (including one from Edna Ferber).
    - Correspondence, 1950; 50 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Letters from Thomas Mann, Rose L. Rashmir, Helen Gahagan Douglas, Chas. H. Thompson, Will Maslow, Anton Smole, and Edward R. Roybal. Some letters refer to Cecil Palmer.
    - Correspondence, 1951 January-May; 42 items. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Letters from Carl F. Stover, William Wyler, Porter Sargent, Harry Barnard, John Valleau, Leon Henkin, Mark Graubard, and others. Some letters refer to The Nation article, "Knights in Shining Buicks."
    - Correspondence, 1951 June-December; 27 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Letters from Clifford J. Durr, Ella Winter, Grace McDonald, Irmgard Lenel, Vernette Landers, Will Rogers, Jr., John B. Thompson, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1952 January-July; 21 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Letters from Geraldine Stern, H. Arthur Klein, Dudley Nichols, Porter Sargent, and others. Also includes a typewritten statement concerning Sidney Buchman and HUAC.
    - Correspondence, 1952 August-December; 13 items. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Letters from Clyde T. Ellis, Angus Cameron, Richard W. Petherbridge, John M. Pickering, George E. Bodle, J. M. Domenach, and others. Also includes a report by Graeme C. Moodie.
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953; 31 items. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Correspondence relating to McWilliams's being accused of communist leanings.
    - Correspondence, 1953 January-September; 33 items. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      Letters from Howard H. Quint, Charles D. Hornig, Alex Blumstein, Elizabeth Partridge, Dorothy Sterling, and others. Also includes a manuscript by Maury Maverick.
    - Correspondence, 1953 October-December; 35 items. (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Letters from Joseph W. Aidlin, Howard H. Quint, Maury Maverick, Mary Grooms, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1954; 23 items. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Letters from Albert Einstein, William Wyler, Robert Leonetti, Richard Morgan, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1955-1956; 6 items. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Robert W. Kenny, Guy Endore, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1957-1974; 12 items. (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Correspondence relating to McWilliams's exemption for jury duty.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1959; 8 items. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1959; 9 items. (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Letters from Andre Schiffrin, Bob Eckhardt, Jay S. Goldenberg, Bosley Crowther, Maury Maverick, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1960; 9 items. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Letters from Wright Mills and others. Also includes and a letter from McWilliams to Eleanor Roosevelt.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1962; 14 items. (Box 27, Folder 6)
      Letters from Friedrich Pollock, James S. Pope, Joe Dolan, Harry Girvetz, and others. Includes letters written by McWilliams in response to charges of communist leanings.
    - Correspondence, 1963; 11 items. (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Letters from Harry Simmons, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1964; 31 items. (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Letters from Hubert H. Humphrey, Kenneth B. Keating, Irving Bernstein, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1964-1966; 35 items. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1965; 11 items. (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Letters from Lois Phillips Hudson, Russell Nixon, Norman Mailer, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1966; 25 items. (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Letters from David B. Lord, Drew Pearson, Edward M. Kennedy, Bernard Reich, and J.F. Powers, Herb Frank, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1967; 25 items. (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Letters from H. Arthur Klein, Leslie R. Colitt, Maxwell Geismar, Robert E. Kellar, D.B. Luten, Edward W. Lewis, Ray Southworth, Alan Lawson, Alan Hensher, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1968; 47 items. (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Letters from H.H. Wilson, William Appleman Williams, Eugene J. McCarthy, Adlai E. Stevenson, Patrick J. Buchanan, Edward W. Lewis, James Aronson, Tristram Coffin, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1969; 36 items. (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Letters from Carl Cohen, George Core, Margaret Maxwell, Steve Murdock, Alice B. Hoskins, Ethyle M. Hawk, Brenda (Goldie) Weisberg Meckler, Jerome Cavanagh, and others. Also includes a letter to Carolyn Caddes in which McWilliams's discusses the Tenney Committee.
    - Correspondence, 1970; 42 items. (Box 27, Folder 15)
      Letters from John D. Rockefeller IV, Charles A. Graham, Chanler A. Chapman, Melvin B. Yoken, Peter de Lissovoy, Leo P. Ribuffo, Jack D. Rittenhouse, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1971; 28 items. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Letters from Eugene J. McCarthy, Edward W. Lewis, C.P. Larrowe, Carl Cohen, Jackson J. Benson, Dwayne E. Walls, Richard O. Boyer, Sam J. Ervin, Richard Kluger, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1972; 43 items. (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Letters from Steve Murdock, Brenda (Goldie) Weisberg Meckler, Irving Louis Horowitz, John R. Dunbar, Gerard Piel, Barbara Probst Solomon, J.K. Obatala, Guy T. Nunn, Harold Rubin, Hannah Josephson, Andrew Levison, Clay Steinman, Dan Hammack, Howard Costigan, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1979; 60 items. (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, primarily concerning McWilliams's mugging. Includes letters from Corliss Lamont, Maxim Lieber, Edward W. Lewis, Hannah Josephson, Arthur Miller, Stanley Mosk, Art Seidenbaum, Phil Kerby, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1973; 21 items. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Letters from Stanley Mosk, Harry G. Mendelson, Kenneth Millar, Joe Goulden, Virginia E. Wilson, Helen Gahagan Douglas, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1974; 42 items. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Letters from Kevin Starr, John Platts Mills, Mary Inman, James Aronson, W.H. Ferry, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1974; 9 items. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Letters, handwritten and typed notes, and an invoice concerning Iris McWilliams's mugging on June 10, 1974.
    - Correspondence, 1975 January-July; 34 items. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Letters from Joel Rothschild, Frances Putnam Fritchman, Suzanne Hunsucker, Sam J. Ervin, Rose Altman, Edward W. Lewis, J.K. Obatala, Lee Lowenfish, Joseph Wershba, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1975 August-December; 36 items. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Letters from Roberta Perry, Cora Weiss, Bill Whitehead, James Weinstein, Marvin E. Frankel, James Bassett, J.S. Holliday, and others. Also includes a signed agreement.
    - Correspondence, 1975-1978; 18 items. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Correspondence concerning McWilliams's oral history interview as part of the University of California, Los Angeles's Oral History Program. Also contains oral history guidelines, a contract, an outline, and queries.
    - Correspondence, 1976 January-July; 41 items. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Letters from Lawrence E. Larson, J.S. Holliday, Alan Reitman, Helen Mears, David Cort, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1976 August-December; 31 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Letters from H. Arthur Klein, M. Margaret Anderson, Matthew J. Bruccoli, Grace Schulman, Mary Matheson Wills, Clay Steinman, Janet Stevenson, Landon Morris, James Bassett, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1977 January-May; 33 items. (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Letters from Samantha Connell O'Neill, Wayne Warga, Elinor Langer, Albert S. Broussard, Pete Wilson, Alvah Bessie, Raymond Rector, Nora Sayre, and others. Also includes signed agreements.
    - Correspondence, 1977 June-August; 25 items. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Letters from J.S. Holliday, Janet Stevenson, Stephen H. Fritchman, Harry Bridges, John R. Crowe, David J. Thompson, Robert R. Alonzo, Mrs. H.H. Wilson, and others. Includes the galleys for McWilliams's article entitled, "George Sanchez: Teacher, Scholar, Activist."
    - Correspondence, 1977 September-December; 18 items. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Letters from E. Harburg, Joseph G. Jorgensen, J. Edward Schamberger, Philip M. Stern, and others. Also includes 4 pages of typed notes.
    - Correspondence, 1977-1979; 25 items. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Correspondence primarily concerning McWilliams's being a Regents Lecturer at the University of California Riverside. Also includes a few newspaper clippings.
    - Correspondence, 1978 January-April; 39 items. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Letters from Celeste MacLeod, Philip M. Stern, J. Edward Schamberger, William Wingfield, Mrs. Malcolm Cowley, John Breasted, H. Arthur Klein, Sybil H. May, Mary Ellen Leary, Clay Steinman, John A. Britton, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1978 May-September; 49 items. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Letters from Theodore Brown, Casley McWilliams, Maureen McCutcheon, Craig Scharlin, Lilia Villanueva, James Aronson, David J. Thompson, Bruce Henstell, Howard Costigan, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1978 October-December; 40 items. (Box 29, Folder 8)
      Letters from Sandy Close, Tom Gaddis, P.C Morantte, Tristram Coffin, Lester Cole, Thomas Sanchez, R. Freeman Butts, Donald Paneth, Harry Bridges, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1978; 5 items. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Letters relating to the Earl Warren Civil Liberties Award bestowed upon McWilliams by the ACLU Foundation of Northern California at their Bill of Rights Day Celebration. Also includes a program, and a clipping.
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980; 24 items. (Box 29, Folder 10)
      Correspondence concerning McWilliams's appointment as Lecturer in the Department of History at the University of California, Los Angeles. Also includes some materials on the Chicano Studies Center.
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980; 21 items. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Primarily letters of congratulations for The Education of Carey McWilliams and/or denunciations of Arthur Schlesinger Jr.'s review of it. Includes letters from Harry Barnard, Abram Eisenman, Emery Nanasy, Clay Steinman, James Storrow, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1979 January-February; 37 items. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Letters from Jeffrey W. Limerick, Landon Morris, David J. Thompson, Margo McBane, Bruce Henstell, Thomas P. Carter, Vernette Landers, J. Edward Schamberger, Simon Bourgin, Bruce Jackson, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1979 March-May; 27 items. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      Letters from Mae Galarza, Abram Eisenman, Peter Gessner, Don Gold, Emery Nanasy, Stanislaw Ehrlich, T. M. Pearce, Susan Nall Bales, P.C. Morantte, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1979 June-August; 34 items. (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Letters from J. Edward Schamberger, Howard Lachtman, Gordon DeMarco, Dusty Sklar, Gary May, Patrick Griffin, Janet Stevenson, David Cort, Cedric Belfrage, M. Stephen Schwartz, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1979 September-December; 37 items. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      Letters from Leonard Leader, Frederick Valentine, Dan C.A. Smith, Rex Wilcox, Henry Geiger, Pam Whalen, Brenda (Goldie) Weisberg Meckler, Howard Lachtman, Mary Cleveland, Maurice Dunbar, Melvin H. Bernstein, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1980 January; 39 items. (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Letters from Celeste MacLeod, Dennis Laurence Cuddy, Howard Lachtman, Henry Geiger, Frank A. Rowe, Herbert Shapiro, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1980 February-March; 34 items. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Letters from Celeste MacLeod, Stanislaw Ehrlich, Linda B. Hall, Frederick Valentine, Philip Stern, Richard Louv, Sondra Blake, Louis E. Wolfson, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1980 April-June; 35 items. (Box 30, Folder 8)
      Letters from Stanley K. Sheinbaum, Dennis Laurence Cuddy, Stanislaw Ehrlich, Don Gold, Louis E. Wolfson, W.H. Ferry, and others.
  - 2D. Publisher correspondence, 1942-1980; 1 box
    This subseries contains letters and correspondence with McWilliams's major publishers. Materials include legal and financial documents, such as contracts. For additional publisher correspondence related to the publication of specific titles, see the monograph files (Subseries 6E). Items are arranged alphabetically by publisher, then chronologically.
    - Greenwood Press (1 of 4), 1967-1976; 21 items. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Greenwood Press (2 of 4), 1967-1969; 27 items. (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Primarily concerning North from Mexico.
    - Greenwood Press (3 of 4), 1970-1972; 45 items. (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Much of which mentions North from Mexico. Also includes 1 item of correspondence between McWilliams and The Author's League of America, Inc.
    - Greenwood Press (4 of 4), 1973-1980; 29 items. (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Much of which mentions North from Mexico.
    - Grossman Publishers, Inc., 1966-1978; 22 items. (Box 31, Folder 5)
      2 letters, a signed agreement, and royalty statements for The California Revolution.
    - Hart Publishing Company, Inc., 1971-1975; 12 items. (Box 31, Folder 6)
      Also includes a typewritten manuscript by McWilliams entitled, "Strikes: A New Perspective," and clippings.
    - Little, Brown and Company (1 of 5), 1942; 52 items. (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Much of which mentions Ill Fares the Land.
    - Little, Brown and Company (2 of 5), 1950-1954; 15 items. (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Primarily concerning The Education of Carey McWilliams.
    - Little, Brown and Company (3 of 5), 1963-1974; 39 items. (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Also includes a typewritten manuscript of McWilliams's introduction to the 1964 edition of Brothers Under the Skin.
    - Little, Brown and Company (4 of 5), 1942-1980; 46 items. (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Royalty statements. Also includes one from Faber & Faber Ltd.
    - Little, Brown and Company (5 of 5), 1942, 1950-1951; 4 items. (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Signed agreements.
    - Peregrine Press (1 of 4), 1970-1971; 47 items. (Box 31, Folder 12)
      Much of which mentions Factories in the Field. Includes a letter from Cesar Chavez.
    - Peregrine Press (2 of 4), 1972-1974; 44 items. (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Much of which mentions Southern California. Includes a quote from Cesar Chavez about Factories in the Field.
    - Peregrine Press (3 of 4), 1975-1979; 46 items. (Box 31, Folder 14)
      Includes a letter from Morrow Mayo.
    - Peregrine Press (4 of 4), 1971-1979; 9 items. (Box 31, Folder 15)
      Royalty statements, signed agreements, and a catalog.
    - Simon & Schuster, Inc. (1 of 2), 1976-1979; 26 items. (Box 31, Folder 16)
      Concerning The Education of Carey McWilliams. Includes typewritten notes, an outline, endnotes, and a selected bibliography.
    - Simon & Schuster, Inc. (2 of 2), 1977-1979; 7 items. (Box 31, Folder 17)
      Royalty statements for The Aspirin Age.
    - W.W. Norton & Company, Inc., 1968-1979; 22 items. (Box 31, Folder 18)
      2 letters, and royalty statements for Indians in America by John Collier.
- 3. Division of Immigration and Housing, 1939-1964; 1 box
  This series contains papers, reports and manuscripts relating to McWilliams's tenure as Chief of the Division. Other DIH materials may be found in his notebooks (Subseries 1C, box 17, folder 3), the scrapbooks (Subseries 1D), the monograph files (Subseries 6E, box 82, folders 5-11), and within the general correspondence files (Subseries 2C, box 25, folders 11 and 12). Files are in chronological order, with the exception of undated materials, which are filed alphabetically at the beginning of the series.
  - Essay. "Current housing problems in California", undated; 3 items. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Typewritten manuscript by McWilliams.